With this, you'll have
这样 你就有两个
two lab projects in hand.
实验室的项目在手
That makes you
那你未来
a big shot in our industry
就是咱们这个行业的
for the future.
大拿了
So, how do you feel about it?
怎么样
Where will I work?
在哪儿
Still in Beijing?
在 还在北京
Yeah, in Beijing.
对啊 在北京
Yiduo,
一朵
first of all,
首先呢
I want to thank you
我感谢你对我的
for your support and trust.
支持和信任啊
However,
但是呢
I still hope you can fulfill
我还是希望你能够兑现
your initial promise.
最初的那个承诺
Our lab is now
我们实验室 挂牌了
officially listed and operational.
正常运营了
Then, I'll go home.
我就回家了
Don't worry.
你放心
Now that
就我现在
I have the experience here,
有了在这儿的经历
finding a job back home
我回去找工作
should be quite easy.
应该是挺容易的
Li Lin.
师哥
Your potential goes far beyond this.
你的能力绝不止于此
Don't always think about going home.
你不要老想着回家
You're at the prime age
你现在正是科研人员
for a researcher.
最好的黄金年龄
It's the best time to produce results.
正是出成果的时候
I'm not exaggerating.
我没有夸张地说
I always knew
我之前就觉得
you were
你是一个
very capable.
非常有能力的人
But after working together
但是我们这次
this time,
合作了之后
your abilities
你的能力
exceeded my expectations.
超出了我的想象
Every day,
你每天都在
you surprise us.
给我们制造惊喜
Li Lin, you're really amazing,
师哥 你真的很棒
you know that?
你知道吗
No need to flatter me;
你不用捧我
I'm very aware
我自己什么水平
of my own level.
我非常清楚
What I told you earlier,
我刚才跟你说的
I've seriously thought it through.
我是认真考虑过的
How about this:
要不这样好吧
let's wait until next month
等下个月
when our lab is
我们实验室挂牌了
officially listed and operational.
运营起来了
I really need to go back.
我真的要回去一趟
Seriously.
真的
or I won't feel settled
要不然我在这儿工作
working here.
我心里面也不踏实啊
What do you think?
你说呢
I understand.
明白了
Forget what
刚才这个消息
I just told you.
就当我没说
Li Lin.
师哥
I have more good news.
我还有个好消息
Want to hear it?
你要不要听
More good news?
还有好消息啊
What is it?
怎么
Letting me go home
让我回家
for a break?
休假啊
You're thinking too small.
格局小了
Hello?
大姐
I thought I was seeing things!
我以为我眼花了呢
When did you get back?
什么时候回来的
Surprised?
惊不惊喜呀
Why did you come back?
你怎么回来了
So suddenly?
怎么那么突然啊
I had to come back.
我必须得回来了
If I didn't, you all
我再不回来的话
would've forgotten me.
你们都快把我给忘了
Well, it wouldn't have gone that far.
那 那倒也不至于
Really? He doesn't know me anymore.
什么不至于啊
I've been coaxing him for ages,
这小家伙跟我不熟了
yet he won't sleep.
哄半天都没哄睡着
Seriously?
是不是呀
Did you take the early flight?
早班机回来的吗
Yes, early flight.
早班机
Today, Daddy's going to
今天爸爸
spend the whole day
要花一整天的时间
getting to know you better,
跟你好好地熟悉熟悉哦
Little Grape.
小葡萄
You don't love me anymore?
你 你是不爱我了吗
Why do you say so?
为什么
Shouldn't you get to know
你不应该先跟你老婆
your wife first?
熟悉熟悉吗
Jealous?
吃醋啦
Come here, my big baby.
来来来 大宝贝
Let's catch up.
熟悉熟悉
I've missed you so much.
想死你们了
We missed you too.
我们也想你
I'm back.
回来了
Ms Xu,
许女士
we went back and conducted research
我们回去做了调研
and reviewed the live stream.
和直播复盘
We believe that
我们认为
if you and Dongzi
如果你要是和东子
team up as a couple,
组成了姐弟搭档的话
the Dongzi family fans
我们东子家族的粉丝
will be very receptive.
接受度会很高
And your commercial value
而且你的商业价值
will increase.
也会有所提升
This would be
对你来说
very beneficial for you.
也是非常有利的
Relax,
放心啦
I have no interest in you.
我对你呀 没意思
The contract.
合同
Sure, let me take a look.
好 我看一下
Sign this contract,
签了这个合同
and here's the deposit.
这是定金
Mengxin, isn't that sincere enough?
许姐姐 我够有诚意吧
Let me share this good news
那我把这个好消息
with my husband.
跟我老公说一下
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是是是
Look, look at Mommy.
看看 看看妈妈
Mom.
妈妈
Where's Jing?
大姐呢
Went grocery shopping?
买菜去了吗
No, she went back home.
回老家了
Did you say something unpleasant again?
你又说什么难听话了
Drove her away?
又把她气走了
What unpleasant thing?
说什么难听话呀
Am I that kind of person?
我是那样的人吗
She has been here
大姐在这儿
looking after the kids
看着孩子
for so long.
这么长时间也挺辛苦的
She needed a good rest,
我让她回去
so, I let her go back.
好好休息休息
Besides,
再说了
I took a month off.
我休了一个月的假
You took a month off?
你休假了
A whole month?
一个月吗
Yeah, a month.
一个月
Don't tell me you're unemployed again?
你该不会又失业了吧
Can't you wish me well for once?
你盼我点好 行不行啊
Well, normally,
那本来嘛
what boss would
哪个老板能给员工
give an employee a month off?
放一个月的假呀
Ms Mei would.
梅老板喽
No way.
那不可能
That she-devil?
那女魔头
Did something happen between you two,
你俩该不会有了啥事
and you ran back?
你跑回来了吧
Is your pregnancy hormone
你这孕激素是不是
acting up again?
又高了
Then speak properly to me.
那你好好跟我说嘛
Don't talk nonsense.
不要瞎说
Now that our lab
这不现在我们实验室
is operating normally,
运营都正常了
I was allowed to take a month off.
这才让我请了一个月假
So, are you staying home
所以你这一个月
for the whole month?
是全在家吗
Yes, the whole month.
全在家
Not going anywhere.
哪儿也不去
I'm reclaiming my lost
我要夺回我失去的
family status.
家庭地位
Go for it!
加油
What are we doing?
我们在干吗呀
We're fist-bumping.
我们在碰拳头
Come on,
来
Here.
来来来
Come on.
加油哦
Let's do it again!
再来一个
Here.
来
Let me hold you.
妈妈抱抱
I'll give you to Mom, okay?
妈妈抱抱 好吧
Okay?
好不好
Or do you want Daddy?
还是爸爸抱
Okay.
好的 好的
Just a quick hug,
就抱一会儿啊
and then give him back to me.
再还给我
If you want to
想要夺回
reclaim your family status,
家庭地位的那个
go cook.
做饭去吧
Hungry already?
饿啦
Let me hold him a bit longer.
再让我抱一会儿
Be good.
乖 来
Go get to know your dad better.
快跟你爸爸熟悉熟悉啊
Here.
来来来
I'll cook for you both later.
一会儿给你们做饭
You smell so good.
香嘞
Wanzhen,
婉真
what's wrong with you?
你怎么了
Did something happen
你和于海
between you and Yu Hai recently?
最近是不是发生了什么
Don't tell me old feelings have rekindled?
不会是旧情又复燃了吧
No way.
怎么可能
Then what's going on?
那这怎么回事
Are you planning to
你这是要和所有的
go against all the investors
投资人作对
to help Yu Hai?
去帮于海
Mr Zhou.
周总
I'm just being realistic.
我这是实事求是
This is a rational judgment
我这是根据
based on Blue Ocean's
蓝海目前的情况
current situation.
做出的理性判断
Although Blue Ocean didn't
蓝海虽然这一次
meet the conditions of the bet this time,
没有达到对赌条件
I don't think it's the best choice
现在我们投资方
for us investors to cash out and leave.
选择了短期套现离场
I don't think
我不觉得这是
this is the best decision.
最好的选择
So, you're standing by Yu Hai?
那你就是要挺于海了
I'm not standing by anyone.
我没有要挺谁
I'm doing this
我这么做
based on my understanding
只是基于对蓝海的
and judgment of Blue Ocean.
了解跟判断
Blue Ocean is just
蓝海不过是
one project for Yaohui Co.
耀辉的一个项目
We have
我们还有很多
many others.
其他的项目
There's no need to offend
没有必要为了一个项目
all the investors for one project.
得罪所有的投资人吧
True,
是
it's just a project
这个项目对我们来说
for us.
只是一个项目
But for its founder,
但是对它的创始人来说
it's ten years of his life's work.
是他十年全部的心血
We must take it seriously.
我们必须认真对待
Wanzhen,
婉真
I think you've
我觉得你对
invested too much energy into Blue Ocean.
蓝海投入了太多的精力
It's not worth it.
不值得
If the founder
如果这个创始人
wasn't your ex-husband,
不是你的前夫
would you care this much?
你会这么在意吗
Of course I would.
当然会
I'm a professional investor.
我是职业的投资人
This is my professional judgment.
这是我做出的专业判断
Then are you willing to bet with me?
那你敢跟我赌吗
Bet on what?
赌什么
If you believe in
如果你相信
Blue Ocean's future,
蓝海未来的发展
then temporarily give up
那你暂时放弃
your position as Investment Director
投资总监的职位
and your partnership.
和合伙人的身份
Hand over all your projects
交出手里所有的项目
and leave Yaohui Co.
离开耀辉
Join Blue Ocean
去蓝海入职
as a shareholder representative.
当股东代表
Achieve the project goals
达到项目书的成绩
and prove your investment vision.
证明你的投资眼光
Then I'll let you come back.
我让你回来
If you fail, don't ever come back.
达不到 永远别回来
Go down with Yu Hai.
和于海共沉沦
This is your only chance.
我只给你这次机会
Do you dare to bet?
你敢赌吗
What's wrong?
怎么了
Were the contract terms
他给你签的合同条款
he offered harsh?
苛刻吗
How's the profit sharing?
收益咋分成
Make a guess.
你猜
How would I know?
我哪儿知道啊
No profit sharing.
不分成
Why should I share with him?
凭什么跟他分呀
He's helping you for free,
他白帮你
bringing in traffic, and
给你带流量 让你挣钱
letting you earn money. No profit sharing?
不分成
He must have taken a liking to you.
看上你了吧
I didn't sign with him.
我没跟他签
Why should I share?
凭什么跟他分啊
You didn't sign?
没签
Why didn't you sign with him?
你没跟他签
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
do you want me
你到底想不想
to sign with him or not?
让我跟他签
I've thought it over.
我想好了
Why should I sign with him?
干吗要签给他呀
We can do it ourselves
咱们俩自己好好做
just fine.
也能做出来的
I'll talk to my sister tomorrow.
明天我就去找我姐
I don't believe
我就不相信
without him,
不靠他东子
I can't make it.
你老婆我成不了
Honey,
老婆
I admire you so much.
我太崇拜你了
Without you, I, Jia Haowen, am nothing.
没有你我贾浩文是个屁
No.
不
You're my husband.
你是我老公
Happy now?
开心了
That's more like it.
这还差不多
Who was that just now,
刚才是谁呀
glaring at me?
跟我吹胡子瞪眼的
Now you're tough.
现在厉害了
Try being fierce with me again.
你再跟我凶一个
No profit sharing.
不分成
Just these five items?
就这五件吗
Yes.
就这些
Just these five?
就这五件啊
There are more on the way.
路上还有呢
The ones that my folks in hometown bought
我老家买那些
are still en route.
都在路上呢
Because I paid
因为我给他们打了
for ten items.
十件的钱呢
Yeah, fine.
对啊
Quickly, unpack them all.
行 赶紧都把它拆开
Then put them
然后把这个
in Xin's room,
放到心心那个屋里头
along with
跟那个没卖出去的
the unsold ones.
都放在一起
Unpack them all.
都把它拆了
Unpack everything.
都把它拆开 都把它拆开
In-law!
亲家母
Be quick.
快快快
I'm here!
我来啦
Well...
那个
Did you buy these too?
你们也买啦
Come, come.
来来来
Give them to me.
来 给我 给我
I was thinking of you,
我这是惦记你们
so, I brought some local specialties
从老家带点土特产
from back home.
来看看你们
Why are you here again?
你怎么又来啦
I wanted to see you.
我看看你们啊
I missed you.
想你们了
Look at all these things.
你看看这些东西
In-law,
亲家
I bought some too.
我也买了
This time,
我这次啊
I mobilized
是把东北的七大姑
all my relatives
八大姨呀
from the northeast
全动员起来了
to support us.
让他们支持一下
Right, right.
对 对
Same here.
我也是
Back home,
我在老家啊
I got all my relatives, friends,
让老家那个亲戚朋友
and neighbors
街坊邻居
to buy some.
全买了
I paid for everything.
钱我出的
Same with us.
我们也是
Yeah.
是啊
We paid too.
钱也是我们出的
I told them not to send to me;
我没让他们寄
just keep it
我说你们留着
for themselves.
自己使吧
I didn't expect it.
我就没想到
I thought
我以为吧
I was just buying for them.
我就给他们买了
You know what?
你知道吗
Some even sent them back.
有的还都给寄回来了
Have some fruit.
吃水果啊
The kids have it tough.
孩子们不容易
Exactly.
就是
When I went to their live stream,
我到那他们直播间看
I saw them putting on
我就看他们那个
and wiping off lipstick
拿那个口红
repeatedly
抹了擦 擦了抹
until their lips were chapped.
那嘴皮都破了
Yeah,
是啊
Haowen too.
浩文也在抹
Can you believe
你说一个大男人
a grown man doing that?
抹那玩意儿
I actually think it looks pretty good.
我觉得还挺好看的呢
Those two kids,
你说这俩孩子
their company
当时办的公司
was booming back then.
办得那红红火火的
Then suddenly, the company was gone.
突然这公司就没了
I mean...
你说
I'm really worried about them.
真替他俩担心啊
I'm afraid
我怕他们从此以后
they might be mentally crushed
受精神打击
and never recover.
消沉下去
What can we do?
这咋整啊
But look at them now.
你看现在
So much better.
多好啊
Yeah,
是啊
they're back on their feet.
俩孩子又起来了
Life's back to how it was,
这小日子又回到从前了
and things are going well.
现在还弄得还挺好
Exactly.
就是
Right?
是吧
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
life will only get better.
日子肯定越过越好
Yeah,
是啊
keep it up.
就这么干
And turn things around.
咸鱼翻身
How's it?
行不行
Not good.
不行
I mean it.
真的不太行
Why not?
怎么真的不太行
When you were little,
你小时候
your baby food
你的辅食
was made by me.
就是爸爸我给你调的
Look how well you've grown.
你看你长这么大了
Was I eating your baby food
那我是一直都
the whole time?
吃你辅食吗
That's all in the past.
你那都是过去式了
Things are different now.
现在都不一样了
So, how should baby food
那你说这辅食
be made now?
应该怎么做
Here's how we do it now.
我们现在都是这么做的
First, peel a boiled egg,
先剥一个鸡蛋
then take half the yolk.
然后半个蛋黄
Add two spoonfuls of rice cereal,
两勺米糊
one spoonful of mashed potatoes,
一勺土豆泥
and one spoonful of carrots.
一勺胡萝卜
Be careful not to give too much.
千万不敢多了
Babies have small stomachs,
小孩胃口小
only as big as a fist.
就拳头那么大
If you overfeed,
你要给他喂多了
you'll stretch his stomach.
就把他胃口撑大了
Do you want my little brother
你想让我弟
to become chubby?
变成小胖子啊
Where did you
你这一套一套的
learn all this?
是从哪儿学来的
We've been doing this
你不在的时候
since you weren't around.
我们都是这么做的呀
So, what else
那我不在的时候
have you learned
你们到底还学了
while I wasn't here?
多少东西啊
Oh, so much more!
那可太多了呀
It must have been tough on you
我不在的时候
while I was away.
真是辛苦你们了
The pressure to learn was intense.
学习压力太大了
Alright,
行了
since I'm back now,
我既然回来了
leave all this
这些事
to me.
都交给我
You just focus on your homework.
你好好做作业去
I've finished my homework,
我正是因为做完了
so, I'm free to supervise you now.
才能来监督你啊
Have I fallen so low at home
我现在在家里
that I need you
已经沦落到
to supervise me?
被你监督的地步了
Inspection.
检查
It's called
那叫
-appreciation. -Appreciation.
欣赏
Right, appreciation.
对 欣赏
Is that okay?
欣赏 行吗
You're still mixing that cereal?
还拌你那糊呢
I've wasted my words.
我都白说了
Do it the way I told you.
按我说的做
You're still supervising!
你这还是监督啊
How should it be done? Repeat it.
怎么做 再说一遍
First, peel a boiled egg.
先剥一个鸡蛋
Half the yolk, two spoons of rice cereal,
半个蛋黄 两勺米糊
one spoonful of mashed potatoes...
一勺土豆泥
How many eggs?
几个鸡蛋
One egg.
一个鸡蛋
Then...
然后
half the yolk.
半个蛋黄
Two spoonfuls
两勺
of rice cereal.
米糊
One spoonful of mashed potatoes,
一勺土豆泥
one spoonful of carrots.
一勺胡萝卜
See?
你看
Did you really think I wouldn't get it?
你以为我真不会啊
Your dad's a top student!
你爸是学霸
You're still trustworthy,
你还是值得信赖的
Comrade Li.
老李同志
Let's begin.
开始
I get you.
我懂你
Why didn't you sign?
你为什么没有签啊
Do you want me to sign
你到底想让我签
or not?
还是不想让我签啊
I just want to ask.
我就想问一下呀
He said he wanted to team up,
他说要组搭档
but I'm not considering it.
我不考虑
I don't want to form a fake duo
我不想组这种假搭档
just to earn money from fans.
赚粉丝的钱
Besides,
再说了
you're my only partner,
我的搭档只有你
just you, my husband.
我老公一个人
You're the only one in my heart,
我的心里只有你
not her.
没有她
You have to believe
你要相信
that my feelings are real.
我的情意并不假
Honey,
老婆
come here.
来
What for?
干吗
Come on.
来呀
Is it our wedding anniversary?
结婚纪念日吗
No.
不是吧
It could be.
也可以是
Come on,
来
the kids are asleep.
孩子都睡了
A rare opportunity
难得的机会
for just the two of us
我们俩在这儿
to watch a movie,
看会儿电影
have a drink,
喝一点
and relax.
放松一下
Movie?
看什么电影啊
Didn't you see me
你没看我在那儿
going through documents over there?
看资料呢吗
What documents?
看什么资料啊
About Mengxin?
梦心的事
Didn't you arrange to meet tomorrow?
不是约好了明天见吗
Not about Xin.
不是心心
Yu Hai.
于海
He's asking you to work?
他让你去上班
He wishes!
他倒想呢
He even wants me
还想让我当
to be the content director
整个蓝海集团的
for the entire Blue Ocean.
内容总监呢
Did you agree?
你答应了
No.
没有啊
So, are you discussing it
那你这是要
with me now?
跟我商量一下
Not really.
也没有啊
It seems my standing in this family
看来我在家庭的地位啊
is rather precarious.
甚是堪忧
No, you've already
不是
reclaimed the power at home.
你已经夺回掌家大权了
But I just don't think this is
是 我是觉得这个事情
something that needs your input.
它没有必要跟你商量
Given our situation, it's not feasible.
咱家条件不允许呀
You're in Beijing right now.
你看你现在在北京
If I take this job,
我要再出去那什么的话
what will happen to the kids?
这 俩孩子咋办
Won't this family fall apart?
那这家不就散了吗
But if our family conditions
那要是我们家庭条件
allowed it?
允许呢
Even if they did, I wouldn't go.
允许我也不去
Why not?
这又为什么
You have no idea.
你不知道
Blue Ocean's situation is now complicated.
蓝海现在的情况很复杂
When he acquired Xinmiao,
他收购新苗的时候
he agreed to a capital bet.
答应跟资本对赌
But he failed,
结果失败了
and now they're restructuring.
现在正在整改
If they can't fix it this time,
如果这次改不好的话
Yu Hai will be kicked out.
于海都是要滚蛋的
So why should I go?
那我干吗去啊
Work there for a couple of months,
上两月班
then pack up and leave?
卷铺盖卷儿
It's not worth it.
我犯不上的
Yeah.
是
Besides,
再说了
I'm not Huang Sisi.
我又不是黄思思
I can't do things she did.
能这个那个什么的
Huang Sisi was never
黄思思本来能力就不行
that capable anyway, right?
是不是
You're capable,
你能力倒是行
but you don't have the energy.
但你精力不行
Can I help?
我行不行
How can I help?
你看 我能帮点啥
Blue Ocean doesn't seem
蓝海好像
to have a healthcare division, does it?
没有医疗板块的业务吧
It's Yu Hai's fault.
还是于海不行
After all this time,
这么久了
his business expansion skills
这拓展业务的能力
are still lacking.
这么差
Exactly!
那是
My husband's vision is much better,
还是我老公眼光好嘛
right?
是不是
Let's not talk about this anymore.
不说这些事了
Right now,
就现在
let's switch to another world.
我们换一个世界
We can't.
换不了
No,
不是
listen.
你看
Yu Hai has already come to me.
这于海都找到我了
At least we're still old classmates,
再不济还是个老同学呢
right?
对吧
I've got to
我怎么也得
come up with a plan for him,
给他弄个方案
so, he can manage for a couple of months
让他对付两月
until he finds a content director
找 有时间找个
or something.
内容总监什么的
Right?
是吧
No, we're not
不是 我们就
in that much of a rush.
不差这点时间吧
Even if you want to,
弄
you can do it
看完了 喝完了
after watching the movie while drinking.
再对付他
But it's getting late.
那都几点了
They're waiting for a lifeline.
人家还等着救命呢
You're saving him,
你救他命
but what about my feelings?
那我的情绪
Shouldn't you take care of them too?
是不是应该照顾一下呢
Alright, alright.
好好好
Give it a swirl.
来 晃一下
Okay, fine.
行了
You can watch on your own.
你自己看吧
Okay.
好
Well...
那 这
From what I've learned
这我 这两天的经验
over the past few days,
告诉我
the all-in-one
还是那个
diapers are still
穿的那一体式的
the best.
纸尿裤好
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗
Because they're
它 它舒服
comfortable and breathable.
它透气
Li Lin.
姐夫
I'm telling you,
什么
those are not environmentally friendly.
那都不环保我跟你说
Why not?
怎么不环保
I've been using them,
我用到现在我发现
and I've found them very effective.
它非常好用
Are you done
这
yet?
你有完没完
You've been
一个
talking about a lousy diaper for ages.
破尿裤说了半天
Hurry back home and help your wife.
你赶紧回家帮媳妇弄吧
Come back from Beijing.
从北京回来
How is she going to take care of two kids?
俩孩子怎么照顾啊
You'll call her
你打电话
to change diapers?
让她换纸尿裤啊
I want to come back,
我也想回来
don't I?
是不是啊
I'm
我这不是
working on it.
想办法呢
Yeah.
对呀
Let me tell you something, Haowen.
我跟你说个事 浩文
Go ahead.
说
Just don't tell anyone else.
你可别出去说啊
Who would I tell?
我跟谁说啊
Come to see your brother.
过来看弟弟
But I still can't tell you,
我还是不能跟你说
you big mouth.
你这个大嘴巴
If you know,
你知道了
everyone will know.
外面人都知道
You're so chatty. This intellectual type
你啰啰嗦嗦的
is really hard to deal with.
这个知识分子真受不了
Right?
是吧
How's Xin's
你家心心那个直播
live stream going?
怎么样了 搞得
I'm not telling you either.
我也不告诉你
Why not
这有什么
tell me about it?
好不告诉我的呀
You're not telling me,
你都不告诉我
so, you go first.
你先说
Let me tell you,
我跟你说
we're doing great now.
我俩现在可好了
We're back to the old storage unit,
又回到以前的小仓库
doing some small business.
做点小买卖
It's tough,
虽然辛苦
but we're making money
但我们挣钱挣得
and feeling secure about it.
可踏实了
We're in the honeymoon phase again.
我俩现在像初恋
Great, great, great!
挺好 挺好 挺好
I can tell from your spirits
我一看你这个精神状态
that things are really good.
就知道
That's great.
真好
You two aren't planning for
你们俩不会奔着
a third child, are you?
三胎去吧
Well, you guess.
那你猜
Is this something I should guess?
这是靠我猜的吗
Yes.
对
You have to make it happen yourself,
你得自己实现呢
right?
是不是
We're having a little brother.
我们还要弟弟呢
Pacifier.
安抚奶嘴
Pacifier. You can't keep sucking on it.
安抚奶嘴 你不能再叼了
After two years old,
两岁以后
you can't use it anymore,
就不能再叼了
because it affects
因为它影响那个
the growth of teeth and gums.
牙齿和牙床的那个生长
You've been doing this live streaming
你这直播也做了
for over half a year now.
大半年了
How's it going?
感觉如何
Pretty good.
挺好的
It's tiring,
累是累了一点
but it feels secure.
但是感觉很踏实
Look,
你看啊
Haowen and I are doing everything together.
我跟老贾现在
Selecting products, shipping,
什么都一起
restocking, live streaming.
选货 发货 上货 直播
It feels like we're back to
找回了当初
the early days of starting our business.
创业时候的感觉
That's good enough.
差不多就行了啊
Your brother-in-law is still in Beijing.
你姐夫还在北京上班呢
With my brother-in-law gone,
我姐夫不在
you must feel lonely, right?
一个人难受了吧
Bored, right?
无聊了吧
Frustrated, right?
憋得慌吧
Come on,
来呀
join us.
一起呀
Can't do it.
干不了
Live streaming really isn't for me.
直播真不行
I'm not asking you to live stream.
没让你直播
Asking you to be a partner.
让你当合伙人
That's even worse.
更干不了了
I'm just not cut out
天生就不是
to be a boss.
当老板的料啊
Didn't you want to sign with a company?
没想签个公司吗
A company approached me,
有公司来找
but I wasn't interested.
我不乐意
Think about it.
那你说
Once you sign with a company,
这公司签了之后
the control is all in their hands.
主动权都在别人手里
I'd be working for someone else,
我给人打工
sharing the profits.
我还跟人分成
What's in it for me?
我图什么呀
What Haowen and I have going now is great.
我跟老贾现在这样多好
The only thing is,
无非就是
we lack some professional expertise.
专业性差了一点
So, I'm thinking of
这要不 就想找一个人
finding someone
帮我指点指点
to guide and plan things.
策划策划
That's why I'm asking you.
所以找你嘛
But I'm not professional enough.
我又不够专业啊
Aren't you in new media?
你不是新媒体吗
Between you and me,
这话就咱俩说
new media and live streaming sales
新媒体和直播带货
are two different things.
那可是两个行当
Don't go embarrassing myself out there.
别上外边丢人去
So, you just don't want to help me.
就是不乐意帮我
Yes,
对
I don't want to.
就是不乐意
So, I find someone else.
所以找别人帮你
Else...
找别
Who?
找谁呀
Who can help me?
找谁帮我
A former subordinate of mine
我以前一个手下
named Xia Xiaohe.
叫夏小荷
She's a good kid,
那孩子人很好
and most importantly, she's hardworking.
最重要的是很吃苦耐劳
She's been
她呢
working for a big streamer
这一年多 也在一个
for over a year,
大主播吧 算是
doing operations.
在他那儿做运营
I talked to her,
然后我也问她了
and she's willing to come help you.
她也很愿意过来帮你
She thinks starting from scratch
觉得从零做起的话
might give her more room for growth.
可能更有发展空间吧
I knew you wouldn't leave me hanging.
我就知道
Doing good deeds
你不会不管我的
without leaving your name, huh?
做好事不留名啊
Here she is, He!
这儿呢 小荷
Hello, Meng'an.
你好 梦安姐
Hello.
你好
Hello, hello!
你好 你好
You must be Hot Mom, right?
您就是辣妈许阿姨吧
Yes, yes.
对对对
Xu Mengxin, my sister.
许梦心 我妹妹
Hello, hello.
你好 你好
Hello.
你好
So, what do you think? Any ideas?
怎么样 有什么想法吗
I reviewed Hot Mom's
我看了辣妈许阿姨的
account.
这个账号
I think
我觉得呢
your persona
你这个人设
needs to be more defined.
需要更加的清晰
Based on current market trends
根据现在市场的规划
and your personal vibe,
以及您个人的一个气质
I've crafted a persona
我给您提炼出了一个
of a bankrupt noblewoman for you.
破产贵妇的人设
It can showcase
既能体现出
your excellent taste.
你很好的品味
And at the same time,
另一方面又可以拉近
it can bring you closer to your audience.
你和用户的一些距离
Bankrupt noblewoman?
破产贵妇
That's good.
这个好啊
Better than Hot Mom.
比辣妈许阿姨要好
No.
不是
Wait a second...
你先等会儿啊
Is it good?
好吗
It's great!
好啊
Simple, eye-catching.
简单明了 吸睛
And it fits
而且跟我现状
my current situation perfectly.
非常符合
Maybe we shouldn't
咱以前的事
mention the past.
是不是就不提了
While it fits,
你这 符合归符合
you should also think about Haowen.
你也得考虑一下浩文吧
Bankrupt?
破产
What's wrong with being bankrupt?
破产怎么了
It's true, we are bankrupt.
那确实是破产了
He's still buying
那他现在拿货
on credit.
还跟人赊账呢
I make the decisions on this.
这个事我说了算
It's settled.
就这么定了
Starting tomorrow,
明天开始
I'm the Bankrupt Noblewoman.
我就是破产贵妇
And you're the noblewoman's sister.
贵妇她姐
Fine.
在呢
This face mask
这款面膜啊
isn't from a middleman channel.
不是中间商渠道
It's not from a department store either,
不是商场渠道
but directly from the factory.
而是工厂渠道
Guaranteed the lowest price online.
保证全网最低价
Those who are interested
喜欢的宝宝们呢
can check out the first link.
可以下一号链接
This face mask
看一下啊
is
这款面膜呢
gentle
它的成分是
and non-irritating.
温和无刺激的
I used it
之前我在哺乳期的时候
while breastfeeding.
就用它
Now my sister
现在我姐姐啊
is pregnant,
是个孕妇
and she can use it too.
她也照样可以用它
Try this.
试试这个
What's this?
这什么东西啊
A prop.
造型
A scapegoat.
背锅侠
What's the scapegoat for?
背锅侠干吗
To give the audience a hook.
给观众一个激点啊
Remember.
记住了
It's your turn.
到你了
Link one is for this face mask.
一号链接是这款面膜
Next, we're moving on to link two.
然后我们上二号链接
It's
是
a lipstick set
我老公拿来的
brought by my husband.
这一款口红套装
I mentioned this lipstick gift box
口红礼盒呢
to everyone earlier.
我当时有跟大家讲过
This is going well.
播得不错
How's it going?
怎么样
How many face masks have sold?
面膜成交多少单了
A lot already.
很多了已经
Much higher than the past few days.
比前两天高很多了
The two of them sitting together
他俩坐一起
works really well.
效果比较好
It's especially good.
特别好
Dear audience...
各位家人
Press your lips together.
抿一下
How does it look?
可以吗
Makes your teeth look whiter.
显得你牙都白了
Does it look good?
好不好看
Everyone, hurry and click the link!
各位宝宝 快点上链接
Shade 416, Rotten Tomato,
四一六号烂番茄
on link two.
二号链接
shade 416, Rotten Tomato.
四一六烂番茄
This office
这间办公室啊
has a great view
视线好
and excellent lighting.
采光也好
That's why I reserved it
所以我
especially for you.
专门把这儿留给你
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Are you heading out on a trip?
你这要出差啊
Yes,
对
I'm off to the airport
去机场
to interview
去集中面试几个
a few content directors.
内容总监
See if there are any suitable candidates.
看看有没有合适的人选
What about Meng'an?
梦安呢
Did you ask her?
你问过她吗
She was the first one I approached.
我第一个找的就是她
She told me that
她跟我说呀
with her child being so young,
孩子现在小
she just doesn't have the energy.
精力不够
I can understand that.
这我也能理解
Besides,
况且
given Blue Ocean's current situation,
蓝海现在这情况
it's not right
拉她下水
to drag her into this.
不太合适
Wanzhen,
婉真
I have to thank you
我得谢谢你
for standing by me in this way.
你用这种方式来力挺我
Otherwise,
要不然啊
those investors would've
我就让那些投资人
kicked me
把我从蓝海
out of Blue Ocean by now.
给扫地出门了
I'm just trusting my investment instincts.
我只相信我的投资眼光
I didn't expect
没想到
that you'd still...
你还能对我
But if I lose this bet,
但如果这次我赌输了
what about your career?
那你的职业生涯怎么办
This is only temporary.
这只是暂时的
Once Blue Ocean gets back on track,
等蓝海走上正轨
I'll return to the investment field.
我还是要回到投资行业
As long as you follow the new plan
你只要按照新的计划
and meet the performance goals,
完成业绩条款
it'll benefit both of us.
对你我的发展都有好处
But I heard from Mr Zhou
但我听周总说
that if this project fails,
如果这个项目弄砸了
your career
那你的职业生涯
is over too.
也就结束了
Don't listen to him.
别听他的
It's not that dramatic.
没那么夸张
Wanzhen,
婉真
for Blue Ocean,
为了蓝海呢
I lost you
我这十年
for
把你
ten years.
弄丢了
But rest assured,
但是你放心
this time, even if it costs me everything,
我这次就算是拼上命
I won't let you down again.
我也不会再辜负你了
Of course,
当然了
if
这个
both of us screw this up,
如果咱俩都干砸了
then we'll sell the house
那咱就把
in the suburbs
郊区那房子卖了
and go home
咱俩回家呀
to have triplets.
生三胞胎去
Stop it.
你快打住
Go catch your flight.
赶你的飞机去
Wait for me.
等着我啊
Why are you going to Blue Ocean?
你为什么要去蓝海啊
Blue Ocean
蓝海是我们
is an investment of Yaohui Co.
耀辉公司投的
I'm going as a shareholder representative,
我去当股东代表
just a normal reassignment.
算是正常调动
I don't understand your investment stuff,
你们投资的事我不懂啊
but I know
但是我知道
you must have the right to refuse.
你肯定有拒绝的权利啊
Tell me the truth.
你跟我说实话
I can't let it go.
我舍不得
Over these ten years,
这十年
Yu Hai built Blue Ocean,
于海创立蓝海
sacrificing his family
撇家舍业
and dedicating himself fully to his work.
全心全意地投入事业里
As his ex-wife,
从家庭的角度来说
I hate him.
我痛恨他
But
但是
from an investor's perspective,
从投资人的角度来说
I still admire him.
我还是有些钦佩他的
It's not just Yu Hai as a person,
不单是指于海这个人啊
but also the years
还有他这么多年
of hard work he's put in.
努力地付出
It's worth cherishing.
还是值得珍惜的
Entrepreneurship, hard work,
创业 付出 努力
and effort are inevitable,
这是必然的
but this reason
你这个理由
doesn't convince me.
说服不了我
Don't be fooled
别看于海平时
by Yu Hai's usual lightheartedness.
嘻嘻哈哈的
Deep down,
其实
he's still
他骨子里
a very proud person.
还是个挺骄傲的人
I once tried
我曾经试图
to break that pride,
打破他这一份骄傲
but now
但是
I have to protect him.
我现在不得不去保护他
Because he was once
因为他曾经
someone important
在我和孩子心中
to me and my child.
是那样的存在
If he fails this time,
如果他这次失败了
I'm afraid
我怕他
he'll never come
就再也不会来
to see me or our child again.
见我和孩子了
But you don't have to
那你也没必要
gamble your career
拿自己的职业生涯
on this.
陪他去赌吧
I'm not gambling,
我不是在赌
which is why I came to you.
所以来找你
I just want to
我只是想用这样的方式
buy Yu Hai
来为于海
more time in this way.
争取更多的时间
You managed Xinmiao from the start,
新苗是你一手运营的
and you're familiar with Blue Ocean.
你对蓝海也不陌生
After all,
毕竟你们是
you've been rivals for years.
那么多年的对手
You must understand it well.
你不会不了解吧
If you become the content director
如果你来蓝海
at Blue Ocean,
做内容总监
we will definitely win.
我们一定会赢
Nothing is absolute.
万事没有绝对
And Yu Hai should have
而且我的情况
told you about my situation.
于海应该也跟你说了
I know,
我知道
but we can't
但是我们不可能
be housewives forever.
一辈子做家庭主妇啊
I'm a living example.
就像我
This is actually
其实这一次对你来说
a good opportunity for you
是一个重返职场的
to return to the workforce.
好时机
You don't have to answer right away.
你不用急着答复我
Give yourself some time
给自己一点时间
to think it over.
好好考虑一下
After all,
这毕竟
this isn't something
不是你一个人
you can decide on your own.
能决定的事情
Still not asleep so late?
这么晚了都还不睡啊
Hubby.
老公
Even if you're helping out,
就算是帮忙
you don't need to stay up all night.
也不需要熬夜吧
It's past midnight.
都后半夜了
There's no need for this.
犯不着吧
Not really.
也不是
I just couldn't sleep.
就是睡不着嘛
I met with Wanzhen yesterday.
昨天见了婉真了
She told me something,
她跟我说了些情况
and I think she and Yu Hai
我觉得她跟于海现在
are really having a tough time.
确实挺不容易的
She and Yu Hai?
她跟于海
What?
怎么
Did they remarry?
他俩复婚了
No,
没有
but they're tied together now.
但他俩现在绑一块儿了
What do you mean by tied together?
绑一块儿是什么意思
Wanzhen is now
婉真
Yu Hai's investor.
现在是于海的投资人
If Blue Ocean fails to meet
蓝海这次对赌如果
its performance targets in this bet,
再业绩不达标的话
Wanzhen's career
婉真的职业生涯
will be over too.
也就跟着结束了
So, don't you think
那你说
I should really help them out?
我不得好好帮帮他们哪
Yes,
对
of course, they need help.
那是得帮他们啊
What's your plan?
你有什么打算
I actually came up
我其实
with a content execution plan
弄了一个有关蓝海的
for Blue Ocean.
内容执行方案
But after all,
毕竟
I'm not in the position
我也不在其位嘛
to say much.
也不好多说
I'm just thinking of
我就想说
giving them this plan
把这个方案
and letting them
给他做出来之后
evaluate
拿给他们
and choose
让他们自己
on their own.
评估选择得了
What if you were in the position?
那你要是在其位呢
If I were in that position?
在其位
I'd execute it with full force.
在其位就上执行力啊
I can't guarantee
就我说的这个
that my plan would
我不敢说
double Blue Ocean's performance,
能让蓝海的业绩翻倍
but it will definitely
但是达标
meet the targets.
肯定是没问题的
Are you 100% sure?
你有百分之一百的把握
I can't say 100%,
那不敢说
but 80% for sure.
但八十还是有的
So, what if
那你要是
I stay home to take care of things,
我在家照顾
and you go execute the plan?
你出去执行呢
You're not lying to me again, are you?
你是不又骗我了
You didn't come back
你这回回来
for a vacation
根本就不是休假
you're unemployed again, right?
就是又失业了 是吗
How could you, Li Lin?
你怎么能这样呢 李临
Are we still a couple?
咱俩还是不是两口子了
Can't you be honest?
能不能说点实话
So, what if you're unemployed?
失业怎么了
It's not like it hasn't happened before.
咱又不是没失过
Do you think I'd ever despise you?
我还能嫌弃你是怎么的
You...
你
You're still laughing?
你还笑
What's so funny about this?
这有什么值得笑的呀
We're talking about unemployment.
失业啊
Yeah,
对
not funny at all.
不值得笑
Alright, I'll be honest with you.
我跟你说实话吧
No. I should hold on for a few more days.
我还是撑两天吧
Holding on for a few more days?
还撑两天
Then your hair will turn white,
再撑头发都白了
and we'll run out of food at home.
家里粮食都没了
Do you know that?
你知道吗
You're the pillar of this family
你是家里的顶梁柱啊
now.
现在
Is hair really that easy to turn white?
头发那么容易白吗
I'll hold back.
我克制一下
Don't worry.
你别着急啊
I'm officially telling you now.
我现在正式地告诉你
I've been reassigned back here.
我被调回来了
Li Lin.
师哥
I have more good news.
我还有个好消息
Want to hear it?
你要不要听
More good news?
还有好消息啊
What is it?
怎么
Letting me go home
让我回家
for a break?
休假啊
You're thinking too small.
格局小了
Mr Ma's lab
马院长的实验室
is preparing for an upgrade,
准备升级改造了
and he needs you.
他需要你
Excited?
高兴吧
Excited my foot!
我高兴你个头
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你怎么不早说呀
Do you know how conflicted
你知道这段时间
I've been during this time?
我过得有多纠结吗
I've been dreading the thought that
我生怕一个电话来了
one phone call would take you away again.
就把你又给叫走了
Do you think it's been easy for me?
我容易吗 我
It's been really hard.
特别不容易
I've seen it.
我都看见了
I just wanted to
我就是
tease you a bit.
想逗你一下
I don't want to be teased anymore.
我不想再跟你逗了
Alright, alright,
好了 好了 好了
I won't tease you anymore.
不逗了 不逗了
But I'm telling the truth.
但是我说的是真话
Excited?
高兴吧
Yeah, a little.
那还是有点的
I'm back.
回来了啊
Honey,
老婆
you have to go.
你得去
Let's not talk about
先不说朋友
whether to help a friend or not.
帮忙不帮忙的事
But I think you should go out
但是我觉得你应该
and pursue your career.
出去搞事业
You've helped me succeed once;
你成就了我一回
now I want to help you succeed.
我也想成就你一把
I don't understand
你搞的这专业
your field,
我不懂
but I know my wife.
但是我了解我老婆
Home isn't
家里
your stage;
不是你的舞台
the outside world
外面
is where you belong.
才是你的天地
It's not as easy as you make it sound.
也没你说得那么容易啦
Taking on a task in a crisis isn't easy.
临危受命 不好搞的
What if I mess it up?
万一我弄不好怎么办呢
We'll do our best.
我们就尽力搞呗
Even if it doesn't work out,
就算是不成
there'll be no regrets.
也没有遗憾
At least we'll have been true
至少我们对得起自己
to ourselves and to our friends.
对得起朋友
I'll go make the milk.
我去冲奶
I'll hold the baby.
我抱孩子
Some say
有人说
that women in their forties
四十岁的女性在职场
have natural advantages in the workplace.
有着天然的优势
They
她们
know their direction,
明方向
understand the rules,
懂道理
have experience,
有经验
and know their limits.
知分寸
Others say
也有人说
that as we age,
随着年龄的增长
our life's entanglements increase,
我们的人生羁绊
making it harder
会越来越多
to achieve significant success.
很难再有大的作为
I want to say,
我想说
you're all right.
你们说得都对
Because
因为这些
I've experienced all of this.
我都经历过
In fact,
甚至
I'm still going through it.
正在经历
You're unemployed now,
你现在失业
and I'm at home awaiting childbirth.
然后我在家待产
What will we eat
家里吃什么呀
and drink?
喝什么呀
Middle age
人到中年
is indeed tough.
确实举步维艰
It's hard for us to make big changes
对自己的工作和生活
to our work and life.
我们很难做出大的改变
Because we have aging parents
因为我们上有老
and young children to care for.
下有小
Then we'll have the baby.
那就生吧
Mommy, I love you!
妈妈 我爱你
But
但是
we still have
我们仍旧有一颗
a passionate heart,
热烈的心
wanting to
想要把这个日子
live a better life.
过得更好
Keep going! Keep going!
加油 加油
Believe in us,
请相信我们这些
the backbone of society.
社会的中坚力量
And believe in yourself.
也请你相信自己
We have the support of our families.
我们有家人的支持
Take this.
拿着
Why are you back so late?
你怎么这么晚回来呀
You're not asleep?
你们没睡
What do you want to eat?
想吃啥
There's everything in the fridge.
冰箱里啥都有
Small wontons.
小馄饨
I will make them.
爸给做去啊
Then this house should include
那这房子也得算姐一份
your share too. This is your home.
这儿就是你的家
You can live here
你可以理直气壮地
without any hesitation.
住在这儿
Come on, let's go home.
来 回家
No matter what,
不管到什么时候
we'll always be family.
咱们都是一家人
The light at home
家里那盏灯
will always be on for you.
永远为你亮着
And with the help of friends.
更有朋友的帮扶
Come to Blue Ocean.
你到我蓝海来啊
You're just having a baby, right?
你不就生个孩子吗
It's just a hundred days or so.
百十来天的事
I, Yu Hai, can wait.
我于海等得起
Are you really this loyal?
你这么仗义吗
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
Congratulations.
恭喜你
You're hired.
入职了
Thank you, Mr Zhou.
谢谢周总
They may be our weakness,
他们是软肋
but they are also our armor.
但更是我们的铠甲
I'm so scared.
吓死我了
It's okay, don't be afraid.
没事的 不怕
Go ahead and give birth.
生
Don't be scared.
不怕
Dad's here.
爸在
Mom,
妈
this is for you.
这是我为你演奏的
Thank you for raising me.
谢谢你的培养
Thank you, my daughter.
谢谢我的女儿
Though I have to give it my all this time,
我这次就算是拼上命
I won't let you down again.
我也不会再辜负你了
I'm your wife.
我是你媳妇
We'll repay all the debt together.
所有的债我们一起扛
We are in this together.
那咱俩一起扛啊
Of course.
扛
So,
所以
we must use this passionate heart
我们要用这颗热烈的心
to overcome all difficulties
去克服一切困难
and embrace
拥抱
each coming day.
即将到来的每一天
For us,
我们
everything is
时光
just in time.
正好